Frontstage, Backstage & On The Road - Take The Tour
ABBA: The Movie is a comedy, drama, music film directed by Lasse Hallström.
A radio DJ in pursuit of an exclusive interview follows ABBA
during their mega-successful tour of Australia.
Agnetha Fältskog, played by Agnetha Fältskog.
Anni-Frid Lyngstad, played by Anni-Frid Lyngstad.
Björn Ulvaeus, played by Björn Ulvaeus.
Benny Andersson, played by Benny Andersson.
Ashley Wallace, the disc Jockey, played by Robert Hughes.
Bodyguard / Bartender / Taxi Driver, played by Tom Oliver.
ABBA: The Movie is a 1977 mockumentary comedy-drama film about the
1977 Australian tour by the Swedish pop group ABBA.
An international co-production between Sweden and Australia, the film was directed
by Lasse Hallström, who previously helmed most of the band's videos.
Its release coincided with ABBA: The Album, the group's fifth studio album, and features many songs from that album
as well as many of their earlier hits, and one, "Get on the Carousel", unavailable anywhere else.
Theatrically released in December 1977 in Sweden and Australia,
it made its way overseas throughout 1978–79.
The film was a box office success and received positive reviews from
critics, while gaining an enthusiastic response from ABBA fans.
The film explores themes of pop music, music tour,
international relations, music documentary, pop band.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.